<metadata>
  <title><![CDATA[ FTL: MULTIVERSE - THE RENEGADE COLLECTION ]]></title>
  <threadUrl><![CDATA[https://ftlmultiverse.boards.net/thread/35/renegade-collection-version-]]></threadUrl>
  <author><![CDATA[Kix]]></author>
  <version><![CDATA[ 2.3 ]]></version>
  <description>
<![CDATA[ 
PATCH AFTER MULTIVERSE

An equipment expansion pack meant to be used alongside Multiverse. Includes many various weapon and drone concepts considered, for one reason or another, unfitting for the base mod.
While attempting to be balanced, due to the nature of the equipment in this pack as well as the fact it is not part of base Multiverse means there may be a higher variation of balance than usual. The new weapons include those that are niche, too conceptually similar to existing weapons, involve "hard-to-balance" gimmicks, or are just conceptually bizare.
Enemies can also spawn with some of these weapons, blue options are updated to include relevant equipment, and stores + Sylvan will sometimes sell them. Some items also have differing rarities in specific sectors.

Lua Code from Chrono Vortex
Proofreading and refining from Jersee
Special Boss sprite from Laythe
Info icon assistance from LocalResources
Crew drones and Mutant sprite by MoreOrLesser
Federation encounter text from R4V3-0N

//////////////////New Weapons//////////////////
---Heavy Chargegun---
A 3-shot charge weapon that fires 2-damage heavy lasers
---Amp Laser---
A Laser weapon that can be toggled to different power modes to increase its damage, power consumption and cooldown
---Compact Laser---
A fast firing but inaccurate Laser that requires no power to use
---Light Burst Laser---
Though slower charging than the usual Light Laser, this weapon fires its 3 projectiles in rapid succession
---Particle Collider---
A modified Particle Accelerator that trades its fire chance for hefty crew damage
---Magnifier Laser/ion---
A Charge weapon that accumulates damage and status effect chances instead of projectiles
---'Fangtian' Fissure Beam---
A Beam that deals system damage on each tile instead of each room
---'Faucon' Mk 2---
An upgraded RAD beam that can kill crew even more efficiently
---'Bardiche' Beam---
A special Chain Beam that also inherits the properties of an anti-hull Beam
---'Kagiyari' Beam---
A special conservative yari Beam that charges slower but requires no power to run alongside the rest of your build
---Apshyxiator Ion---
A partially piercing ion that creates a guaranteed breach, perfect for accelerating asphyxiation kills
---'Infinity' Ion---
A special adaptive ion that can chain a potentially infinite number of times
---Energy Phaser---
A single shot Energy weapon that pierces shields similar to a Phase Ion
---Energy Flamer---
An Energy weapon with guaranteed fire chances
---'Scorch' Pinpoint---
A fast charging Pinpoint with partial shield piercing that does no damage but starts fires
---'Poniard' Pinpoint---
A decent damage but slow charging conservative Pinpoint
---Shrapnel Bomb---
A special Bomb that spreads system damage to adjacent rooms
---Particle Bomb---
A high system damage bomb with a large fire chance
---Gasoline Bomb---
A bomb that significantly increases fire damage taken on crew hit by it
---Deployment Bomb---
A support Bomb that deploys a temporary repair drone at the cost of a dronepart rather than missile
---Arachno Bomb---
A bizare utility bomb that spawns 2 temporary hatchling allies but does no direct physical damage
--Mutagen Bomb--
A strange bomb that causes crew to mutate, changing them into terrifying mutants
---'Apollo' Missiles---
A missile that does no crew damage but heals allied crew in the room it hits
---'Boreas' Missiles---
A modified Frost missile that trades hullbusting for locking down rooms
---Shrapnel Missiles---
A missile that spreads system damamge to adjacent rooms
---'Epimetheus' Missiles---
A high damage Pre-Emptive missile
---Hazard Sentry---
A new deployment cannon that weakens enemy crew, making them take significantly more damage from hazards
---Virulent Dish---
An anti-bio weapon that affects adjacent rooms as well
---'Baal' Mine Launcher---
A special Mine Launcher which deals phasing ion damage rather than hull damage nad has a unique delay option
---Trifecta---
A unique yet bizare weapon that fires both flak and a heavy laser at once
---Frost Flak---
Similarly to the Frost Lasers, the Frost Flak does both physical damage and locks down rooms
---Assembly Cannon---
A special weapon that produces temporary Combat drones in exchange for a dronepart
---'Ultraburn'---
A short but extremely hot fire Beam, which damages the hull and makes crew take more damage from fires. It even removes fire resistance from crew like Rockmen!
---'Systemshock'---
A peculiar ion weapon that on direct hits spreads ion damage to adjacent rooms
---Flare Launcher---
A quick charging, conservative, and cheap utility weapon that blinds enemy crew and distracts Defense Drones

And more secret weapons to discover...

///////////////////New Drones///////////////////
---Supressor Combat Drone---
A swift Drone that evades anti-drone measures and supress shield layers without damage capabilities
---Thundershock Combat Drone---
A bomb-equipped Toggle Drone that can switch between breach bombs and ion bombs
---'Theseus' Combat Drone---
A Missile drone that requires 3 missiles to deploy
---Scattershot Defense Drone---
A flak based Defense Drone with a quick cooldown but slow projectiles which can target anything
---Extinguisher Crew Drone---
A utility repair drone that extinguishes fires very fast and drains oxygen but is far less efficient at regular repairs
---Voltage Crew Drone---
A utility drone that provides a hefty power boost but decays due to instability
---Overshield Crew Drone---
A shipboard drone that drains power from systems to power shields that it provides to allied crew
]]>
  </description>
</metadata>